VARTIKA SINGH

SUMMARY

A highly compassionate Counseling Psychologist with over 3 years of experience in teaching and counseling. She is highly empathetic, thoughtful and client centered. Compassionately committed to working with clients especially having a broad spectrum of different types of mental health issues. Adept at multi tasking and proactively addressing emotionally intense situation with individual clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CONSULTANT PSYCHOLOGIST AND COUNSELLOR (APRIL 2020 – PRESENT)

Cure fit (https://www.cure.fit/)

CONSULTANT PSYCHOLOGIST (APRIL 2019 – FEBRUARY 2020)

Yourdost Company (https://yourdost.com/)

PGT PSYCHOLOGY CUM SCHOOL COUNSELOR (JULY 2019

-March 2020)Bal Bharti Public School, Gurgaon

Guest Faculty (ASSISTANT PROFESSOR) Bharati College, University of Delhi

Pursuing PhD (University of Delhi)

EXTRA WORKING EXPERIENCE

- 3 months of experience working as a **Research Associate** in **NCERT**.
- Worked as **Creative Content Writer** at India's First onlinemagazine Psychologs.
- Served as a counsellor on COVID-19 Mental health helpline number under **Arogya Seva in collaboration with Karnataka government**.
- Member of Yellow club's School Outreach Program where Iconduct workshops and seminars related to mental health and career related issues.

CERTIFICATIONS

PG Diploma in guidance and counselling, NCERT, New Delhi.



CONTACT

Phone: +91 7524070305

Email: vartik111@gmail.com

Highlights

- Articulate communication skills
- Team management
- Empathetic understanding
- Leadership
- Organized
- Good listening skills

PUBLICATIONS

- Emotional Intelligence and Optimism: Understanding the relationship with health behavior Positive Vistas on Health and well-being ISBN No. 978-93-85777-34-9(publication)
- Emotional Intelligence and Happiness: Does Profession Make A difference? Interdisciplinary perspectives on Health and wellbeing ISBN No. 978-93-86256-63-8(publication)
- Presented Paper at International Conference on public health: Issues, challenges, opportunities, prevention, Awareness (2016)

EXTRA KNOWLEDGE AND QUALIFICATIONS

- Trained in Psychological Assessment specially in TAT, Rorschach, MMPI DAPT, CIS, MAP-T, DAT and other assessments tests and in career counselling.
- Trained in conducting Psychological Assessments of adults and children especially MMPI,16 PF, Malin's Intelligence scale, Beck's Anxiety Inventory, BDI, Bender Gestalt Test and RPM etc.
- Trained in making IEPs for special children.
- Trained in CBT, graphology ,client centered approach and also developing interventions.

EDUCATION

B.A (HONS.) PSYCHOLOGY

Daulat Ram College, North Campus, Delhi University

Marks Obtained: 79.45%

M.A APPLIED PSYCHOLOGY SPECIALIZATION (CLINICAL AND COUNSELING)

Department of Applied Psychology, South Campus, Delhi University

Marks Obtained: 80%

UGC-NET QUALIFIED (2019) Twice.

Diploma in counseling and guidance from NCERT - Overall Grade

<u>**DECLARATION**</u>: I Vartika Singh hereby declare that the above information provided is fully true to my knowledge and believe.

LANGUAGES

- Hindi
- English

HOBBIES

- Poetry writing
- Reading
- Dancing
- Travelling